Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Law Serials TAM.778
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Law Serials
1935-2013
1960-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Amnesty International
National Lawyers Guild
TAM.778
4.9 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes and 9 flat boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Law Serials contains over 180 titles on legal issues in the United States, Europe, and Central America between 1935 and 2013. The bulk of the collection consists of American serials published between the 1960s and the 1980s. Topics include the legal system in the United States, human rights issues, and prison reform.
Arrangement
Serials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to the law drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials, received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Law Serials contains over 180 titles on legal issues in the United States (US), Europe, and Central America between 1935 and 2013. The bulk of the collection consists of American serials published between the 1960s and the 1980s. A large number of the serials consist of publications of the National Lawyers Guild, both the national organization and state chapters, and Amnesty International. Topics include the work of lawyers and judges, reform of the American legal system, and legal rights of American citizens. The collection contains serials published by organizations focused on specific issues, including welfare, prison reform, legal defense for specific individuals, consumer rights, and hate crimes. Large runs of titles include Amnesty International's Matchbox and Amnesty Action, the Bay Area regional office of the National Lawyers Guild's Conspiracy, and the New York office of the National Lawyers Guild's Blind Justice.
Serials (publications); Criminal law -- United States -- Periodicals.; Prisoners -- Civil rights -- United States.; Prisoners -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States.; Lawyers -- United States -- Periodicals.; Human rights.; Public welfare -- United States.
- 1948 Report of Progress: New York State Commission Against Discrimination, Albany, NY (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Abolitionist: WSFSG, Seattle, WA, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Americans for Legal Reform: HALT, Washington, DC, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 2-4, Box 13, Folder 1-3)
- Amicus Populi: Massachusetts Lawyers Guild, Boston, MA, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Amnesty Action: Amnesty International, USA, New York, NY, 1968-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6-8, Box 7, Folder 1-9, Box 13, Folder 4)
- Anarchy: Journal of the Anarchist Pen Pals Unlimited, Montreal, Quebec, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Anvil: California Prisoners Union, Sacramento, CA, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Arbitration Times: American Arbitration Association, New York, NY, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- As the South Goes: Project South, Atlanta, GA, 1997-2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Attica News: Attica Defense Committee, Buffalo, NY, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Attica News: Attica News, Buffalo, NY, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Attica News Service: Attica Defense Committee, Buffalo, NY, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 12-31)
- August 8th Edition: August 8th Brigade Defense Coalition, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Bar None: Bar None, W. Somerville, MA, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1-21)
- Beacon Light: William Kullgren, Atascadero, CA, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Beyond Welfare: Committee for Political Development / Advocators, Detroit, MI, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Blind Justice: National Lawyers Guild, New York City Office, New York, NY, 1971-1988 (Box 8, Folder 1-4, Box 13, Folder 7-8)
- Blind Justice: New York City Chapter of the National Lawyers Guild, New York, NY, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Briefs: Seattle Chapter National Lawyers Guild, Seattle, WA, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- Bulletin on the New York State Attorney General's Committee on Human Relations: New York State Attorney General's Committee on Human Relations, New York, NY, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- By Any Means Necessary: Ruchell Magee Defense Committee, Stanford, CA, Undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
- California Guild Lawyer: National Lawyers Guild, New York, NY, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Call for Justice: Committee For Justice For Domingo and Viernes, Seattle, WA, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- CARE The Refugee Report: CARE (Cooperative for Assistance and Relief Everywhere, Inc.), Atlanta, GA, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- CDF Reports: Children's Defense Fund, Washington, DC, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Center for New Corporate Priorities Newsletter: Center for New Corporate Priorities, Los Angeles, CA, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- CFA News: Consumer Federation of America, Washington, DC, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Champions of the Human Rights Struggle - Fifth Annual Grassroots Tribute: New Afrikan People's Organization, New York, NY, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Common Wealth Fund Quarterly: Common Wealth Fund, Seattle, WA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Commoner: Legal Services Training Center for Massachusetts, Boston, MA, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Connections: First Friends-EDCVP, Elizbeth, NJ, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 1-22)
- Conspiracy: Bay Area Regional Office, National Lawyers Guild, San Francisco, CA, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 8-10, Box 9, Folder 1, Box 13, Folder 11-12)
- Conspiracy: National Lawyers Guild, Bay Area Regional Office, San Francisco, CA, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6-7, Box 9, Folder 2-6)
- Constitutional Protection for the Foreign Born 12th Annual Conference Journal: Los Angeles Committee for Protection of the Foreign Born, Los Angeles, CA, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Constitutionalist: Committee to Protect Convention Action and Preserve the Constitution, Washington, DC, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Consumers Voice: Consumers Education & Protective Association International, Inc., Philadelphia, PA, 1982-1990 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Corporate Crime Update: Center for Corporate Accountability, London, UK, 2002-2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CPSB Newsletter: Committee for Prisoner Support in Birmingham, Birmingham, AL, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Cure-NY Newsletter: New York Chapter of Citizens United for the Rehabilitation of Errants (CURE), Katonah, NY, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Endeavor: War Resisters League, New York, NY, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Equal Defense Alliance: National Lawyers Guild, Seattle, WA, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Ethical Perspectives: Publications Committee of the New York Society for Ethical Culture, New York, NY, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
- FAMMgram: Families Against Mandatory Minimums Foundation, Washington, DC, 1994-2001 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Fighting Back: Youth Against War & Fascism, New York, NY, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
- FOIA, Inc. Pamphlet: Fund for Open Information and Accountability, Inc., New York, NY, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
- FOIAlert: FOIA, Inc., New York, NY, Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Fortune News: Fortune Society, New York, NY, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 26, Box 6, Folder 12)
- Free Terrence Johnson: DC Unite to Fight Back, Washington, DC, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Free the Five Newsletter: Free the Vancouver Five Defense Group, Vancouver, BC, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Freedom Now!: Campaign for Amnesty and Human Rights for Political Prisoners in the US, Chicago, IL, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Freeworld Times: The Murian Foundation for Criminal Justice, Inc., Minneapolis, MN, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
- Gathering - Death Row Voices Both Sides of the Wire: November Belford West / War Resisters League, New York, NY, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Gaycon Prison Newsletter: Gaycon Prision Outreach, Seattle, WA, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- GEO (Grassroots Economic Organizing) Newsletter: EDINA, The Ecological Democracy Institute of North America, Stillwater, PA, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Grassroots Grapevine: Hempstead Chapter of the Long Island Progressive Coalition, Massapequa, NY, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Hapotoc Newsletter: HAPOTOC, Amsterdam, Netherlands, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Human Rights News: Fund for Human Rights, Inc., New York, NY, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Human Rights Yearbook: USSR Academy of Sciences - The Institute of State and Law, Moscow, USSR, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Humanitas: International Human Rights Committee, Menlo Park, CA, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Indigenous & Planning Development Times: Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Pratt Institute, Brooklyn, NY, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Inner City Press: Inner City Press, Bronx, NY, 1988-1994 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
- Inside Out: Prisoner's Progress Association, Ann Arbor, MI, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2, Box 10, Folder 4)
- Intelligence Report: Southern Poverty Law Center, Montgomery, AL, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- IRCD Bulletin: ERIC Information Retrieval Center on the Disadvantaged, New York, NY, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Jericho: UUSC National Moratorium on Prison Construction, Washington, DC, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Jericho: National Moratorium on Prison Construction, Washington, DC, 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
- Jericho: Joint Committee, Portland, OR, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Journal of the American Judicature Society: American Judicature Society, Chicago, IL, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Justice First: Alliance for Justice, Washington, DC, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Justice for Youth: Community Service Society of New York, New York, NY, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Justice Matters: Western Prison Project, Portland, OR, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- JusticeJournal: JusticeWorks Community, Brooklyn, NY, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Justicia: Judicial Process Commission, Rochester, NY, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Labor League News: Labor League for Human Rights, New York, NY, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Law in the Service of Peace: International Association of Democratic Lawyers' Review, Brussels, Belgium, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Law Report: Southern Poverty Law Center, Montgomery, AL, 1974-1991 (Box 14, Folder 10-11, Box 15)
- Legal Journal: National Lawyers Guild Prison Law Project, San Francisco, CA, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Legal Reformer: HALT, Washington, DC, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
- Legislative Gazette: State University of New York College at New Paltz, Albany, NY, 1983-1993 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
- M-CUP: Minneapolis Community Union Project, Minneapolis, MN, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Marion Brothers Action Bulletin: National Committee to Support Marion Bros., St. Louis, MO, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Marion Brothers News Report: National Committee to Support the Marion Brothers, St. Louis, MO, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Matchbox: Amnesty International USA, New York, NY, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 12, Box 10, Folder 8-10, Box 14)
- Matchbox: Amnesty International of the USA, San Francisco, CA, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 13-14)
- Maverick: Minnesota Prisoners Union, Minneapolis, MN, 1975-1979 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- MCC News: Morrisania Community Corporation, Bronx, NY, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Michigan State Bar Journal: State Bar of Michigan, Lansing, MI, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Minnesota Prisoners' Union Newsletter: Minnesota Prisoners Union, Minneapolis, MN, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 6, Box 15, Folder 2)
- Money, Education and Prisons: MEP, Madison, WI, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Moratorium Campaign: Moratorium Campaign, New Orleans, LA, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- N.P.R.A. News: National Prisoners' Reform Association, Cranston, RI, 1974-1977 (Box 15, Folder 3-6)
- N.Y. City Crisis Center Newsletter: NY City Crisis Center, New York, NY, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- NEPA News: New England Prisoners' Association, Franconia, NH, 1973-1976 (Box 10, Folder 12-13, Box 11, Folder 1-3)
- New York City News: National Lawyers Guild, New York, NY, 1998-2003 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- New York Law Journal: New York Law Journal, New York, NY, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- New York Nonprofits: Nonprofit Coordinating Committee of NY, New York, NY, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Newsletter: Poverty / Rights Action Center, Washington, DC, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Newsletter: Kristina Berster Defense Committee, Winooski, VT, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Newsletter: Alternatives to Violence Project, Inc., New York, NY, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Newsletter: Committee for Human Rights in Chile, Seattle, WA, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- NLG / Maurice and Jane Sugar Law Center for Economic & Social Justice: NLG / Sugar Law Center, Detroit, MI, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- North Carolina Political Prisoners Committee Newsletter: North Carolina Political Prisoners Committee, Charlotte, NC, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- North Star News: North Star Fund, Inc., New York, NY, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Nottingham Defence Fund Newsletter: Nottingham Defence Fund, Nottingham, UK, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- November Coalition: The November Coalition, Colville, WA, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 11-14)
- NOW!: National Headquarters of the Welfare Rights Movement, Washington, DC, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- NOW! National Welfare Leaders Newsletter: National Welfare Rights Organization/Poverty/Rights Action Center, Washington, DC, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Open Gate: Open Gate, Stormville, NY, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Organizer: Committee to Rebuild the National Welfare Rights Organization, New York, NY, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Oxfam America News: Oxfam America, Boston, MA, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Palestine Human Rights Bulletin: Palestine Human Rights Campaign, Chicago, IL, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Peace without Prisons: WRL Prison Task Force, New York, NY, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Penal Digest International: National Prison Center, Iowa City, IA, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 6-8)
- People: Public Affairs Office of the City of New York Human Resources Administration, New York, NY, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- People Get Ready: Soledad Brothers Defense Committee, San Francisco, CA, Undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
- People Not Profit: People Not Profit, Homewood, IL, 2012-2013 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- People's Justice / National Lawyers Guild, Southern California Chapter: National Lawyers Guild, Southern California Chapter, Los Angeles, CA, 1971-1982 (Box 6, Folder 7-9, Box 11, Folder 9-10)
- People's News: Greater Upstate Law Project, Rochester, NY, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Peoples' Verdict: National Laywers Guild, Washington, DC, Undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
- PHRA: Poverty and Human Resources Abstracts, Ann Arbor, MI, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Political Prisoners' Relief Committee: Political Prisoners' Relief Committee, New York, NY, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Prison News Service: Prison News Service, Toronto, Ontario, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Prison News Service: Bulldozer, Toronto, Ontario, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Prison Policy News: Epimethian Press & Distribution, Colorado Springs, CO, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Prisoners Solidarity Committee: Prisoners Solidarity Committee, New York, NY, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Provincia de Angola Ordem da Provincia de Malange: Ordem da Provincia de Malange, Lisboa, Portugal, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Public Affairs Pamphlets: Public Affairs Committee, Inc., New York, NY, 1943-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- PUG Newsletter: Prisoners' User Group, Monroe, WA, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- QUASH: Grand Jury Project, New York, NY, 1976-1983 (Box 3, Folder 3, Box 6, Folder 10, Box 12, Folder 3-4, Box 15, Folder 13-14)
- Question Mark: Massachusetts Correctional Institute, Norfolk, MA, Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Radical Caucus in English and the Modern Languages: Radical Caucus in English and the Modern Languages, Cambridge, MA, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Reality Check: Brotherhood/Sister Sol, New York, NY, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Refugees & Human Rights Newsletter: Chruch World Service Immigration and Refugee Program, New York, NY, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Report: Center for Immigrants Rights, New York, NY, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Report for May: Venice Organizing Project, Venice, CA, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Report of the Proceedings of the Status of Political Prisoners Conference: International Labor Defense, New York, NY, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Republikanische Hilfe: Republikanische Hilfe, Frankfurt, Germany, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Resumen Informativo Newsletter: Inter-American Committee for Human and Trade Union Rights, El Dorado, Panama, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Review: International Commission of Jurists, Geneva, Switzerland, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Review of Contemporary Law: International Association of Democratic Lawyers' Review, Brussels, Belgium, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
- Rights of Man: International League for the Rights of Man, New York, NY, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Rigoberta: Rigoberta Menchu Tum Foundation, New York, NY, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- S.C.A.R.'(d) Times: New England Prisoners Association, Portland, ME, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- School Law Newsletter: The School Law Newsletter, Dallas, NC, 1970-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Seniors for Adequate Social Security Newsletter: Seniors for Adequate Social Security, Washington, DC, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Smoloskyp: Smoloskyp, Ellicott City, MD, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Social Welfare in a Changing World: US Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Washington, DC, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- South Sound Alliance: Oregon Coalition of Alternative Human Services, Portland, OR, 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 6-8)
- Southern Fight-Back: Southern Organizing Committee for Economic & Social Justice (SOC), Louisville, KY, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Southland Prison News: Prison Media Fund, Cambridge, MA, 2000-2002 (Box 5, Folder 24-25)
- SPLC Report: Southern Poverty Law Center, Montgomery, AL, 1993-1998 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Sunfighter: Awareness Project, Seattle, WA, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Take It: People for Economic Survival, Leeds, MA, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Taking Liberties: Anarchist Black Cross, London, UK, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- This Month: Labor League for Human Rights, New York, NY, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Thought Bombs: S. Chicago ARA-ABC Zine Distro, Homewood, IL, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Through the Looking Glass: Through the Looking Glass, Philadelphia, PA, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Too Much: Council on International and Public Affairs, New York, NY, 1992-2000 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
- Truth: American Freedom Company, Danbury, NH, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Upton Sinclair's National EPIC News: EPIC Publishing Company, Los Angeles, CA, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Voice of Prisons: Washington State Penitentiary, WA, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Voices for New Justice: Voices for New Justice, Bearsville, NY, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Walkin' Steel: Committee to End the Marion Lockdown, Chicago, IL, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- War Behind Walls: Peoples Press, San Francisco, CA, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Weekly Legislative Digest: State of New York Department of Labor, Albany, NY, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
- Weekly News: New York State Council of Senior Citizens, New York, NY, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Welfare and You: Sacramento Area Chapters of the National Association of Social Workers/California Social Workers Organization, Sacramento, CA, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Welfare Fighter: National Welfare Rights Organization, Washington, DC, 1969-1972 (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Welfare Handbooks: Center on Social Welfare Policy & Law/Poverty/Rights Actions Center, Washington, DC, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Welfare Laws: Center on Social Welfare Policy & Law/Poverty/Rights Actions Center, Washington, DC, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Welfare Mothers Voice: Welfare Warriors, Milwaukee, WI, 1987-1997 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Welfare News: Hudson County Welfare Union, Jersey City, NJ, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Wives' Tales: Park Slope Safe Homes Project, Brooklyn, NY, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- World Report: CARE Headquarters, Atlanta, GA, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- World Report: CARE Headquarters, New York, NY, 1984-1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- World Service Authority News Bulletin: World Service Authority, Basel, Switzerland, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- World Vision Partners: World Vision, Inc., Federal Way, WA, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- YES! A Journal of Positive Futures: Positive Futures Network, Bainbridge Island, WA, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 29)